<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>toxicity on Biology UKZN</title>
    <link>/tags/toxicity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in toxicity on Biology UKZN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:04:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/toxicity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A closer look at secondary metabolites</title>
      <link>/post/secondary-metabolites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/secondary-metabolites/</guid>
      <description>Secondary metabolites manufactured in the secondary metabolism of plants provide many health and economic benefits to humans (Tiwari and Rana, 2015). Primary metabolites include a narrow range of compounds (proteins, carbohydrates, and lipids), whilst secondary metabolites entail a wider range of compounds (alkaloids, steroids, flavonoids, tannins, phenolics, etc.) (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). Most of these secondary metabolite compounds are produced by plants as a defence mechanism against toxins and pathogens from their surrounding environment (Bourgaud et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples of the uses of secondary metabolites</title>
      <link>/post/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/examples/</guid>
      <description>Although plants may survive without the use of secondary metabolites these compound extracts have great advantages:For exampleFigure 1: Shikonine is a red pigment that is manufactured by Lithospermum eryrorhizon cells which has been used for cosmetics such as lipsticks.Figure 2: Vincristine sulphate is manufactured from Vinca rosea and is helpful for treating cancer.Other compounds which are used to treat cardiovascular disorders include Digoxin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>