<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biology UKZN</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Biology UKZN</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview - Plants, biotechnology and metabolites</title>
      <link>/post/metabolites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/metabolites/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Plants have been used as a source of traditional medicine for decades (Fennell et al., 2004). Most plants, especially medicinal plants have antibacterial, anti-inflammatory, antioxidant, antifungal, antischistosomal, anthelminthic, antimalarial and anti-amoebic properties (Fennell et al., 2004). However, purification and extraction processes differ between compounds with technological improvements being needed for more complex compounds. Plant compound extraction is mostly for commercial purposes, for example &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; methods may be used to produce large quantities to meet product demands (Bourgaud et al., 2001). Extracting material from plants has become easier with modern technology, however, there have been very few successful productions of valuable secondary metabolites (Bourgaud et al., 2001).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biotechnology is known to be one of the greatest benefits to humankind and is constantly being improved (Boulter, 1995). Some of the earliest types of biotechnology included agriculture and making beer and bread (Boulter, 1995). Since then, technology has improved greatly; humans have managed to introduce desirable traits into organisms through genetic modification and engineering, especially in plants (Boulter, 1995; Bourgaud et al., 2001). These processes form part of plant biotechnology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cellular metabolism carries out important biochemical reactions with the assistance of metabolites (Hussain et al., 2012). The metabolites that are found in plants are categorized into two categories, namely primary and secondary metabolites (MacQueen, 1988; Hussain et al., 2012). The first category is important for a plant’s growth and development; whilst the second category plays a more vital role in the later stages of a plant’s life by contributing to the plant’s overall survival (Hussain et al., 2012). Secondary metabolite absence may not have short-term gains, however, it may affect the long-term survival of the plant (Hussain et al., 2012).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;callus.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;An example of plant biotechnology. A cell suspension culture showing friable callus (a mass of undifferentiated cells) from the hypocotyl of a plant.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: An example of plant biotechnology. A cell suspension culture showing friable callus (a mass of undifferentiated cells) from the hypocotyl of a plant.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;pathways.png&#34; alt=&#34;Linkages between primary and secondary metabolites. [Click here to see more.](https://www.intechopen.com/books/secondary-metabolites-sources-and-applications/an-introductory-chapter-secondary-metabolites)&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: Linkages between primary and secondary metabolites. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.intechopen.com/books/secondary-metabolites-sources-and-applications/an-introductory-chapter-secondary-metabolites&#34;&gt;Click here to see more.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A closer look at secondary metabolites</title>
      <link>/post/secondary-metabolites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/secondary-metabolites/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Secondary metabolites manufactured in the secondary metabolism of plants provide many health and economic benefits to humans (Tiwari and Rana, 2015). Primary metabolites include a narrow range of compounds (proteins, carbohydrates, and lipids), whilst secondary metabolites entail a wider range of compounds (alkaloids, steroids, flavonoids, tannins, phenolics, etc.) (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). Most of these secondary metabolite compounds are produced by plants as a defence mechanism against toxins and pathogens from their surrounding environment (Bourgaud et al., 2001). According to Tiwari and Rana (2015), the quantity of secondary metabolites produced from mature plants (which have differentiated tissues) &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; have shown to be significantly more than immature plants (which have non-differentiated tissues).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;secondary.gif&#34; alt=&#34;The structures of common secondary metabolites.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: The structures of common secondary metabolites.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For centuries, these compounds have played an important role in traditional medicines, however, their discoveries have often been linked to their high toxicity levels (Bourgaud et al., 2001). Toxic plants applied medically often work more quickly and their benefits are therefore seen more rapidly than those of non-toxic plants (Bourgaud et al., 2001; Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). Secondary metabolites are economically important for the synthesis of drugs, flavourants, fragrances, insecticides, and dyes (Pagare et al., 2015; Tiwari and Rana, 2015). For example, a diterpene alkaloid, Taxol (paclitaxel), is found in the bark of &lt;em&gt;Taxus&lt;/em&gt; trees and is known for its anticancer effects (Hussain et al., 2012). Secondary compounds are very specific as they usually only occur in specific areas within plants (Bourgaud et al., 2001; Hussain et al., 2012). In addition, secondary metabolites are sometimes unique to specific species or taxon groups (Hussain et al., 2012). They generally accumulate in small quantities and are therefore difficult to extract and purify (Bourgaud et al., 2001). This is one of the main reasons why the commercial products produced by these compounds are often very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are secondary metabolites less important?</title>
      <link>/post/importance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/importance/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Secondary metabolites were first distinguished from primary metabolites by Kossel (Bourgaud et al., 2001). The traditional name “secondary metabolites” has existed for decades, but this term may give the impression that these chemicals are of less importance than primary metabolites (Price-Whelan et al., 2006). This is not the case. For example, secondary metabolites used for pollination purposes may not be needed initially, however, once the plant reaches maturity and cannot reproduce asexually the plant relies on these chemicals to attract pollinators to facilitate sexual reproduction (Campbell et al., 2016). To illustrate an example of volatile (chemical pheremones released by plants to attract specific types of pollinators) importance in pollination biology, Campbell et al. (2016) used two &lt;em&gt;Zaluzianskya&lt;/em&gt; flower species. These were pollinated by flies and hawkmoths and have overlapping flower opening times. In this experiment, they found a distinct attraction by hawkmoths to one species over the other due to the combination of flower scent and flower orientation (Campbell et al., 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;hawkmoth.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A hawkmoth visiting the night blooming *Zaluzianskya capensis*.  [Click here to see more.](https://nph.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/nph.13746)&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: A hawkmoth visiting the night blooming &lt;em&gt;Zaluzianskya capensis&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://nph.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/nph.13746&#34;&gt;Click here to see more.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The definition of a secondary metabolite is vague and somewhat confusing. This has stirred a debate on the naming of these compounds (Price-Whelan et al., 2006). However, the compounds found within this group have such a wide range categorized by&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their chemical structure (most of which have rings which contain a sugar)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their composition of nitrogen&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Their solubility&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pathway that is used to produce them (for example, tannins are produced by the phenylpropanoid pathway) (Tiwari and Rana, 2015)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to these shared characteristics, these compounds are rare and specific making it difficult to classify all chemicals within secondary metabolite groups (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). Given these shared characteristics, three main groups can be identified: alkaloids, phenolics, and steroids and terpenes (Tiwari and Rana, 2015).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, ‘secondary metabolites’ have been given a term that is too broad. This is likely because of their often very similar chemical and molecular structure. Therefore, it might be useful to split these compounds into more than one term. One possibility is to group these compounds based on the kind of function they provide to the plant. These categories may include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defence compounds
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chemical&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;physical&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;repair&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stress tolerance compounds&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pollination pheromone compounds&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And supplementary compounds (which may include compounds with unclear or unknown functions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A possible alternative to the current terminology would therefore be to change the term secondary metabolites to &lt;strong&gt;functional metabolites&lt;/strong&gt; whilst retaining the term ‘primary metabolites’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;callus.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;An example of plant biotechnology: A cell suspension culture showing friable callus (a mass of undifferentiated cells) from the hypocotyl of a plant.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: An example of plant biotechnology: A cell suspension culture showing friable callus (a mass of undifferentiated cells) from the hypocotyl of a plant.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples of the uses of secondary metabolites</title>
      <link>/post/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/examples/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;although-plants-may-survive-without-the-use-of-secondary-metabolites-these-compound-extracts-have-great-advantages&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Although plants may survive without the use of secondary metabolites these compound extracts have great advantages:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;for-example&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;For example&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;lipstick.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;**Shikonine** is a red pigment that is manufactured by *Lithospermum eryrorhizon* cells which has been used for cosmetics such as lipsticks. &#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: &lt;strong&gt;Shikonine&lt;/strong&gt; is a red pigment that is manufactured by &lt;em&gt;Lithospermum eryrorhizon&lt;/em&gt; cells which has been used for cosmetics such as lipsticks.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;vincristine.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;**Vincristine sulphate** is manufactured from *Vinca rosea* and is helpful for treating cancer. &#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: &lt;strong&gt;Vincristine sulphate&lt;/strong&gt; is manufactured from &lt;em&gt;Vinca rosea&lt;/em&gt; and is helpful for treating cancer.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other compounds which are used to treat cardiovascular disorders include &lt;strong&gt;Digoxin&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;digoxin.png&#34; alt=&#34;Structure of Digoxin.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 3: Structure of Digoxin.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;sun.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Some secondary metabolites have the ability to protect plants against harmful UV rays (Bourgaud et al., 2001). Here, secondary metabolites are produced by redirecting the primary metabolism in plants leading to protection of leaves from UV rays.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 4: Some secondary metabolites have the ability to protect plants against harmful UV rays (Bourgaud et al., 2001). Here, secondary metabolites are produced by redirecting the primary metabolism in plants leading to protection of leaves from UV rays.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;insect.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Some compounds may release toxins that deter herbivorous insects and animals, for example, **Pyrithrin** is a compound used as an insecticide.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 5: Some compounds may release toxins that deter herbivorous insects and animals, for example, &lt;strong&gt;Pyrithrin&lt;/strong&gt; is a compound used as an insecticide.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;peri.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Madagascar Periwinkel, also mentioned by MacQueen (1988) has useful secondary metabolites (**ajmalicine**) which help lower blood pressure. &#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 6: The Madagascar Periwinkel, also mentioned by MacQueen (1988) has useful secondary metabolites (&lt;strong&gt;ajmalicine&lt;/strong&gt;) which help lower blood pressure.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much has biotechnology evolved since the 1980s?</title>
      <link>/post/biotech-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/biotech-now/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;The struggle with extraction and purification of secondary metabolites is that it is 1) difficult 2) costly and 3) time consuming (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). Third world countries are often not politically or economically stable and so expensive techniques are not easily available to these nations. MacQueen (1988) highlighted some difficulties with the extraction of secondary metabolites and many of those difficulties are still problematic today (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). In addition, the size of natural habitats are decreasing because of anthropical activities which cause global changes (Lewis and Maslin, 2015; Isbell et al., 2017). This causes plants which have specific distribution localities to become extinct (Hussain et al., 2012). Therefore, relying on the plants occurring in natural habitats may not be realistic for the large amounts of produce that is required. Some alternatives or solutions for this increased demand include biopharming and &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;biopharming-or-plant-molecular-farming-pmf&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Biopharming or plant molecular farming (PMF)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process genetically modifies plants for the manufacturing of various pharmaceuticals and industrial products (Elbehri, 2005). For example, genetically modifying tobacco or corn with desired therapeutic proteins could produce vaccines, drugs and antibodies for treating life-long diseases such as cancer and cardiovascular diseases (Elbehri, 2005). The products produced by such methods are referred to as ‘biopharmaceuticals’ or ‘biologics’ (Elbehri, 2005).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of biopharming could be seen as an alternative to current methods or as an implementation in response to the increased demands from the growing human population (Elbehri, 2005; Yadav, 2010). However, this concept has not yet been fully accepted, A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pub.ac.za/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Factsheet-Pub-BioPharming2PRINT3.pdf&#34;&gt;Public Understanding of Biotechnology factsheet&lt;/a&gt; addresses some of the concerns, whilst highlighting the advantages that this implementation could bring about. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The possibility of large scale productions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowered production costs as current technology includes costly machinery and techniques.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The use of plants may include the possibility to produce more complex drugs, especially when compared to those produced in genetically modified animals.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This may be a safer vaccine and antigen production.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A helpful way to increase the availability of vaccines and treatment to third world countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contamination of the food chain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allergic reactions to the products produced.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Negative impacts on non-target organisms (for example, grazers).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workers may be exposed to health risks if exposed to the plants for prolonged periods.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plant dosages may need quality control.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chemicals used to treat the crops may have unexpected outcomes on the final product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/d6m3SoKIStQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;in-vitro-methods&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;em&gt;In vitro&lt;/em&gt; methods&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative solution to chemical synthesis and whole plant based extraction may be the use of sterile environment &lt;em&gt;in vitro&lt;/em&gt; methods. Such methods do not take place inside an organism but rather in a test tube or culture plate. Tissue culture (a process established in the 1960’s) is currently one of the successful methods for extrating secondary metabolites (Tiwari and Rana, 2015). However, even with increased focus on improving biotechnological techniques over the past 30 – 40 years, this method is not perfect (Tiwari and Rana, 2015). An especially difficult aspect in tissue culture is the limited nature and specificity of the secondary metabolites in plants (MacQueen, 1988). Plants often produce secondary metabolites in response to environmental stressors such as pathgens but encourntereing these is very unlikely in sterile environments (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). However, this problem may be solved with the introduction of elicitors (which deceive plants by mimicking the attack of a pathogen or fungus which in turn triggers the production of secondary metabolites), signal compounds, and biotic stresses (MacQueen, 1988; Tiwari and Rana, 2015). Another complexity of using cultures is to find the optimum media, the correct explant (the parent plant which the culture is grown from), and culture conditions such as temperature, pH, oxygen, and chemical precursors, to promote optimum culture growth (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all this, the benefits of tissue culture include 1) a controlled environment with no competition, 2) limited contamination from microbes and insects, 3) increased potential for any type of plant cell division which promotes the possibility of specific metabolite extraction, 4) an increased overall productivity and decreased labour costs and 5) callus cultures allow for extraction of organic compounds (Tiwari and Rana, 2015; Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;tissue.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Basic tissue culture technique.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: Basic tissue culture technique.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hairy root cultures are a type of tissue culture that can also be used to produce secondary metabolites through genetic engineering. &lt;em&gt;Rhizobium rhizogenes&lt;/em&gt; is a bacterium that occurs in soils and has root-inducing (Ri) plasmids (Pistelli et al., 2010). These plasmids alter root growth causing roots to grow irregularly, making it easier to harvest compounds from them (Pistelli et al., 2010). This method has high genetic stability and productivity and is therefore considered useful (Pistelli et al., 2010).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:unnamed-chunk-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;root.png&#34; alt=&#34;An example of Agrobacterium rhizogenes-mediated hairy root culture in *Gentiana scabra*.&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 2: An example of Agrobacterium rhizogenes-mediated hairy root culture in &lt;em&gt;Gentiana scabra&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
