<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Biology UKZN</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Biology UKZN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview - Plants, biotechnology and metabolites</title>
      <link>/post/metabolites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/metabolites/</guid>
      <description>Plants have been used as a source of traditional medicine for decades (Fennell et al., 2004). Most plants, especially medicinal plants have antibacterial, anti-inflammatory, antioxidant, antifungal, antischistosomal, anthelminthic, antimalarial and anti-amoebic properties (Fennell et al., 2004). However, purification and extraction processes differ between compounds with technological improvements being needed for more complex compounds. Plant compound extraction is mostly for commercial purposes, for example in vitro methods may be used to produce large quantities to meet product demands (Bourgaud et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A closer look at secondary metabolites</title>
      <link>/post/secondary-metabolites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/secondary-metabolites/</guid>
      <description>Secondary metabolites manufactured in the secondary metabolism of plants provide many health and economic benefits to humans (Tiwari and Rana, 2015). Primary metabolites include a narrow range of compounds (proteins, carbohydrates, and lipids), whilst secondary metabolites entail a wider range of compounds (alkaloids, steroids, flavonoids, tannins, phenolics, etc.) (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). Most of these secondary metabolite compounds are produced by plants as a defence mechanism against toxins and pathogens from their surrounding environment (Bourgaud et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are secondary metabolites less important?</title>
      <link>/post/importance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/importance/</guid>
      <description>Secondary metabolites were first distinguished from primary metabolites by Kossel (Bourgaud et al., 2001). The traditional name “secondary metabolites” has existed for decades, but this term may give the impression that these chemicals are of less importance than primary metabolites (Price-Whelan et al., 2006). This is not the case. For example, secondary metabolites used for pollination purposes may not be needed initially, however, once the plant reaches maturity and cannot reproduce asexually the plant relies on these chemicals to attract pollinators to facilitate sexual reproduction (Campbell et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples of the uses of secondary metabolites</title>
      <link>/post/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/examples/</guid>
      <description>Although plants may survive without the use of secondary metabolites these compound extracts have great advantages:For exampleFigure 1: Shikonine is a red pigment that is manufactured by Lithospermum eryrorhizon cells which has been used for cosmetics such as lipsticks.Figure 2: Vincristine sulphate is manufactured from Vinca rosea and is helpful for treating cancer.Other compounds which are used to treat cardiovascular disorders include Digoxin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much has biotechnology evolved since the 1980s?</title>
      <link>/post/biotech-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/biotech-now/</guid>
      <description>The struggle with extraction and purification of secondary metabolites is that it is 1) difficult 2) costly and 3) time consuming (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). Third world countries are often not politically or economically stable and so expensive techniques are not easily available to these nations. MacQueen (1988) highlighted some difficulties with the extraction of secondary metabolites and many of those difficulties are still problematic today (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>