<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>in vitro on Biology UKZN</title>
    <link>/tags/in-vitro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in in vitro on Biology UKZN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:04:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/in-vitro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A closer look at secondary metabolites</title>
      <link>/post/secondary-metabolites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/secondary-metabolites/</guid>
      <description>Secondary metabolites manufactured in the secondary metabolism of plants provide many health and economic benefits to humans (Tiwari and Rana, 2015). Primary metabolites include a narrow range of compounds (proteins, carbohydrates, and lipids), whilst secondary metabolites entail a wider range of compounds (alkaloids, steroids, flavonoids, tannins, phenolics, etc.) (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). Most of these secondary metabolite compounds are produced by plants as a defence mechanism against toxins and pathogens from their surrounding environment (Bourgaud et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much has biotechnology evolved since the 1980s?</title>
      <link>/post/biotech-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/biotech-now/</guid>
      <description>The struggle with extraction and purification of secondary metabolites is that it is 1) difficult 2) costly and 3) time consuming (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019). Third world countries are often not politically or economically stable and so expensive techniques are not easily available to these nations. MacQueen (1988) highlighted some difficulties with the extraction of secondary metabolites and many of those difficulties are still problematic today (Class notes, Prof Finnie, 2019).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>